graphcard.com 2016-01-31

# Graphcard - Privacy Statement

| Our mission is to enable merchants and buyers world wide to buy and pay for tangible products and services securely online with or without access to traditional credit cards  
This privacy statement covers the site www.graphcard.com. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they   
should first contact Customer Service Department. Email :customerservice@graphcard.net Customer service mailing address: 8101 Sandy Spring Road Suite 220 Laurel MD 20707 USA

**Information Collection and Use**

GRAPHCARD.COM is the sole owner of the information collected on GRAPHCARD.COM. GRAPHCARD.COM collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

**Registration**  
In order to use this Web site, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to enter contact information such as name and email address, business and home address. We use this information   
to contact the user about services on our site for which he has expressed interest. Users may also be required to provide demographic information such as income level and gender. For your security, all users are required to supply unique user id and password during registration in order to personalize account profile for each member  
In some instances we may ask for user's Social Security No for identification purposes and to perform the site’s service.

**Order**  
We request information from the user on our order form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date).   
This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer’s orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user.

**Information Use**  
We use information collected to register you as Graphcard member. Some of the information such as shipping address, Name and Customer service phone number provided will be made available to buyer and merchants dealing with you during any particular transaction.

**Profile**  
We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, to create a profile of our users. A profile   
stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user’s visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We will not share your profile with other third parties without your consent. Consent is sought at the time of registration or during occasional promotional offers to our members.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to specific information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any   
personally identifiable information while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users log off, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. 

How cookies are used on Graphcard.com 

By setting a cookie on our site, users would not have to log in a password more than once,   
thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookie, they will not be able to use our site nor be able to participate in any of our services. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site for example,   
advertisers. However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. 

**Third Party Advertising**  
The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to users directly and sometimes through a third party ad server  
Information about users’ visit to this site, such as number of times they have viewed an ad   
but not user name, address, or other personal information will be tracked and used to serve ads to users on this site. 

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Graphcard.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

**Log Files**  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for   
aggregate use.. IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to enable our Web-based service. 

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**  
We employ a software  technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of  Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period  at the end of this sentence.  Clear gifs are not tied to users’ personally identifiable information.

Clear Gifs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same Web site or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited “www.graphcard.com”, which uses an advertising company's clear gif, the Web site would match the clear gif's identifier and the advertising company's cookie   
ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. This collected information would then be saved in the database 

In addition, we use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If users would like to opt-out of these emails, please see the Opt-out section. 

**Communications from the Site**  
We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and  username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the  privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of  communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

**Newsletter**  
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

**Service Announcements**  
On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service  related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended  for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not  opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their  account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. Users may opt-out of these communications. Please see our Choice and Opt-out section.

Customer Service  
We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes.

**Sharing**

Legal Disclaimer  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

**Third Party Intermediaries**  
We use an outside credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

**Service Providers**  
We partner with other third parties Verisign to provide specific services. For example, payment gateway When the user signs up for these particular services, we share names, or other contact information such as credit card number, expiration date and AVS code necessary to provide credit card transaction information except for the purpose of providing these services.

**Business Transitions**  
In the event Graphcard.com goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at customerservice@graphcard.net 

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being   
collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party.

**Links**  
This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Graphcard.com, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Surveys  **  
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via   
surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes   
contact information such as name and shipping address, and demographic information such as zip code. Contact information will be used  with the survey to notify the winners and award prizes. Anonymous Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users’   
personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior notice and choice. Though we may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys or contests, they may not use users’ personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

**Tell-A-Friend**  
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend   
about our site, we ask them for the friend’s name and email address. Graphcard.com will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. Graphcard.com stores this information for the sole purpose of sending email   
and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact Graphcard.com at http://www.graphcard.com to request the removal of this information from our database.

**Chat Rooms, Message Boards, and Public Forums**  
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, by posting personal information online that is publicly accessible, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

**Security**  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information.   
When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information such as credit card number and/or social security number, that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape   
Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just ‘surfing’.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must   
re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. 

Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users’ information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, behind a locked cage in a locked facility.   
Be sure that your actual practices are reflected in this section. For example, if your employees are updated on privacy every 6 months, then state that, rather than a statement that is false. Another example, must employees use password-protected screensavers?]

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to customerservice@graphcard.net

**Supplementation of Information  **  
In order for this Web site to properly fulfill its obligation to users   
it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from 3rd party sources.

**Credit Check**  
In order to determine if users qualify for one of our services, we may use their name and social security number to request a credit report. Once we determine a user’s credit-worthiness, this document is destroyed. 

**ID Address Verification**  
We use third party software to verify a user’s identity address to state why it is necessary to verify the user’s identity or address. 

**Purchasing History**  
In order for this Web site to enhance its ability to tailor the site to a user’s preference, we combine information about the purchasing habits of users with similar information from our Merchants to create a personalized user profile. 

**Enhancement of Marketing Profile**  
We purchase third party marketing data and add it to our existing user database to better target our advertising and provide pertinent offers we think our users would be interested in. We use this information to enhance or overlay the ‘profile’ of individual users. This aggregate marketing data is therefore tied to the users’ personally identifiable information. See also the “Profile.”

**Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information**  
If a user’s personally identifiable information changes such as zip code, phone, email or postal address, or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the member profile page or by emailing our Customer Support at customerservice@graphcard.net

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email.

**Contact Information**  
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

Corporate matters, please contact us at: 6701 Democracy Boulevard, suite 300, Bethesda, MD 20817. 

Web site URL [http://www.graphcard.com](http://www.graphcard.com/)  
Email:customerservice@graphcard.net

|
